Guide to the Michael C. Dooling Collection MS 062
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Michael C. Dooling Collection
1990-2014
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Dooling, Michael C.
MS 062
1 Linear Feet 1 box
Materials mostly related to Dooling's research on three cases from the middle 1900s of the unsolved disappearances of Paula Welden, Connie Smith and Katherine Hull.
Content Description
This collection consists mostly of materials related to research for Clueless in New England; other materials include publications by or about Dooling.
Separated Materials
Monographs relating to Connecticut history have been catalogued separately and added to the Connecticut Room collection at WCSU. Seaworthy Timber, Milford Lost & Found, An Historical Account of Charles Island, Milford, CT and Clueless in New England.
Biographical / Historical
Michael C. Dooling received a Bachelor of Arts in Psychology degrees from Western Connecticut State College in 1974 and a Master of Arts in Psychology degree from Southern Connecticut State College in 1978. He worked for the Schick company in Milford, CT in research and development for 21 years. Dooling then became the news librarian for Waterbury's Republican-American and writer of numerous books and articles mostly related to Connnecticut history. Additionally, Dooling has a life-long interest in history and antiquarian books and is currently on the staff of the Mattatuck Museum.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michael Dooling in 2015
Arrangement
Arranged into two series. Research and Publications
Connecticut--History; Missing persons--New England.; Missing persons--Investigation--New England.; Welden, Paula; Smith, Connie; Hull, Katherine
- Research
  Scope and Contents
  Includes research for Dooling's book: Clueless in New England; contains news clipping, and documentation of the disappearances of Katherine Hull, Leah Johnson, Katherine Humphries, Edith Craven, Connie Smith and Paula Welden; also includes general criminology research and materials regarding suspect Alfred Gadette.
  - Criminology - background information, disappearances, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Research regarding criminal investigations, primarily of missing persons.
  - Criminology - profiling victims, 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Edith Craven - Research Notes, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Edith Craven - Clippings, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Gadette (suspect), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Katherine Hull - Research Notes, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Katherine Hull - Clippings, 1874-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Katherine Humphries - Research Notes, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Katherine Humphries - Clippings, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Leah Johnson - Research Notes, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Leah Johnson - Police File, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Leah Johnson - Clippings, 1930-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Long Trail Vermont Vanishings - Research Notes, 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Long Trail Vermont Vanishings - Clippings, 1945-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Includes materials on Middie Rivers, James Tedford, Paul Jepson, and Freida Langer.
  - Connie Smith - Research Notes, 2002-2012 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Connie Smith - Background Related Research, 1892-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Connie Smith - Police File, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Connie Smith - U.S. Dept. of Interior Geological Survey Sharon, CT- New York, 1950 (Oversized folder OS Item 1)
  - Connie Smith - Background Clippings, 1924-1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Connie Smith - Clippings, 1952-2011 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Paula Welden - Research Material, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - Paula Welden - Clippings, 1945-2005 (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
  - Paula Welden - Case Files, 1945-2007 (Box 1, Folder 31-36)
    Folder 31 includes a compact disc containing the police file.
- Publications
  Includes materials regarding Dooling's Web proofreading (AKA The Webster) and articles written by Dooling primarily dealing with Connecticut topics.
  - Publications, 1994-2014 (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
    Materials include: "Words Perfect?" Time Magazine, 1996; "On a First Name Basis" and "Clearing the Smoke: Babbitt's Curious Inscription" The Sinclair Lewis Society Newsletter, 2005; "The Thin Iron Line: The Crimean War Transforms Naval Power" Naval History, 2004; "Department Spotlight: Up Close and Personal with Sensory Evaluation" The Cutting Edge, 1995; "Touch A Life!" The Cutting Edge, 1996; "Super Proofer" MicroScope, 1996; Writer's Digest, 1998; Reader's Digest, 1996; The Art & Science of Shaving, 1994; The Art & Science of Shaving, Japanese language edition, 1994; The Haunting on East 27th, 2014.
  - Connecticut Related Publications, 1996-2014 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Materials include: Seaworthy Timber, 2014; Milford Lost & Found, 2009; An Historical Account of Charles Island Milford, CT, 2006; Clueless in New England, 2010; "Connecticut's Sleepy Hollow" Connecticut Explored, 2012; "Three Generations in the Newspaper Business" Connecticut Explored, 2010; "The Crimean Clippers: American Clipper Ships in French Transport Service" The Log of Mystic Seaport, 1996; "More Than a Meetinghouse" Republican-American, 2010; Milford Living, 2014.